<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Matt Copperwaite</title><link>https://matt.copperwaite.net/</link><description>Recent content on Matt Copperwaite</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>matt@copperwaite.net (Matt Copperwaite)</managingEditor><webMaster>matt@copperwaite.net (Matt Copperwaite)</webMaster><copyright>CC BY-SA 4.0</copyright><atom:link href="https://matt.copperwaite.net/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TV Show Chart</title><link>https://matt.copperwaite.net/showcase/tv-show-chart/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 17:14:32 +0100</pubDate><author>matt@copperwaite.net (Matt Copperwaite)</author><guid>https://matt.copperwaite.net/showcase/tv-show-chart/</guid><description>&lt;p>There used to be a website that did this for you. It seemed to go away. So I decided to write some quick hacks to make my own. It is really bare minimum to get it working.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It started off being nothing good or professional about the code behind the repo. I am not a front-end person at all, other than I like doing a bit of JavaScript from time to time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I personally prefer the IMDb popularity scores, but their API is functionally non-existent. So I wrote some Python to pull all the code together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Originally my plan was to store the episode data objects in maybe S3 or B2 and process the data in AWS Lambdas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However I could never get the Lambdas to complete in time and I was worried if the site became popular I would be paying for bandwidth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I then realised I might be able to store the data in GitHub, but the data as JSON was far too big. I seem to remember reading that there is a 2Gb limit on GitHub repo sizes. So I created my own proprietary format to store the data in a more succinct way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with static sites in GitHub and these work really well with GitHub Actions, commiting the code back to the repo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plus I read an article about grabbing &lt;a href="https://coviddata.github.io/coviddata/">Covid data using GitHub Actions on a schedule&lt;/a>. It really made me want to revisit this work since the data hadn&amp;rsquo;t been updated in months.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also found that GitHub Actions are way more powerful that Lambdas so I could run the scripts in a matter of minutes, which was nice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are definitely some UX improvements I would like to make so it&amp;rsquo;s possible to search for TV shows, but I need to do a bit of professionalisation first.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Filter Annoyances</title><link>https://matt.copperwaite.net/showcase/filter-annoyances/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 17:14:32 +0100</pubDate><author>matt@copperwaite.net (Matt Copperwaite)</author><guid>https://matt.copperwaite.net/showcase/filter-annoyances/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is my first foray in to making uBlock origin. I was at the time, and still do, wanted to remove the cookie and GDPR pop-ups but still use the site. These filters help facilitate that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a couple of built-in ones to uBlock such as &lt;a href="https://github.com/easylist/easylist">easylist cookie&lt;/a> and uBlock Annoyances, but these looked difficult to contribute to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did use &lt;a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/i-dont-care-about-cookies/">&lt;em>I don&amp;rsquo;t care about cookies&lt;/em>&lt;/a> for a little while, which worked fine, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find it&amp;rsquo;s source code anywhere, despite it saying it&amp;rsquo;s open source. So I thought to be safe I would stop using it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m kind of curious about ways you can test and validate uBlock Origin filters. It seems kind of difficult.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also found that the &lt;a href="https://github.com/gorhill/uBlock/wiki/Static-filter-syntax">filter syntax used in uBlock Origin comes from Adblock Plus&lt;/a>, and they can be very imprecise. But the uBlock Origin element picker tool is amazing. Some of the time I use it then copy the generated rule in to this repo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I chose (rather unusually for me) the CC0 license for these filters because I wanted to put them as much in to the public domain as possible, and because they are not really programmatic scripts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The distractions list is purely for things that take me away being productive on sites I use day-to-day. Kind of dark patterns really that keep you on their site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aggressive filter I&amp;rsquo;ve moved away from because it was too difficult to maintain and I kept having to switch off uBlock to see if the page worked, which then meant I saw ads.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Common Sense as Bad Practice</title><link>https://matt.copperwaite.net/blog/common-sense-as-bad-practice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 13:35:32 +0100</pubDate><author>matt@copperwaite.net (Matt Copperwaite)</author><guid>https://matt.copperwaite.net/blog/common-sense-as-bad-practice/</guid><description>&lt;p>It came to me in conversation recently as to how toxic &amp;ldquo;Common Sense&amp;rdquo; is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Common Sense says &amp;ldquo;well, everyone uses X, so we should use X&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Everyone should know this.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But those are fallacies and assumptions that aren&amp;rsquo;t tested or rooted in evidence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Usually Common Sense comes from asking your mates or colleagues, or assuming they think the same as you. However, by doing that you inherit bias in those assumptions. You make decisions that don&amp;rsquo;t hold true, and at best you are likely going to make poor decisions, and at worst create an exclusionary environment &amp;ndash; locking out people who you will want to include.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you believe it is Common Sense, prove it is Common Sense. Test it out. Trial it, and properly. Don&amp;rsquo;t be part of the problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, challenge &amp;ldquo;Common Sense&amp;rdquo; when it is used.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Why is it common sense?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Who else thinks they know that as the answer?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>You should end up with a better solution that is more open and equitable than your assumptions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Assessing Security Practices of 3rd Party products</title><link>https://matt.copperwaite.net/blog/assessing-security-practices-of-3rd-party-projects/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 18:10:32 +0100</pubDate><author>matt@copperwaite.net (Matt Copperwaite)</author><guid>https://matt.copperwaite.net/blog/assessing-security-practices-of-3rd-party-projects/</guid><description>&lt;p>In recent months I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in discussions about whether remote working tools are &amp;ldquo;secure&amp;rdquo; or not. The answer to any blunt question like that is, as always, &amp;ldquo;it depends&amp;rdquo;, but this is as helpful as getting financial advice from YouTube adverts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It struck me that a lot of people interested in IT security often judge tools based upon how many vulnerabilities there are in a product. But lets be accurate here, they are judging it on how many security vulnerabilities are reported, or visible.&lt;/p>
&lt;!--alex ignore white-->
&lt;p>Once the pandemic forced us all to work from home, &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-52115434">Zoom seemed to be the target for every &amp;ldquo;white hat&amp;rdquo; hacker consultancy&lt;/a> &lt;em>generously&lt;/em> giving their time to declare the 0 days they found to news websites, with nothing more in return than their company name to be placed along side the &lt;del>advert&lt;/del> article.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These articles seemingly leading to several instances of &amp;ldquo;Enterprise&amp;rdquo; security teams declaring Zoom as insecure and made attempts to block its usage in their environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But is Zoom unsecure? And does blocking it improve things?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you block Zoom, what will people use instead? Google Hangout? Skype? Chime? WebEx? Some random tool they found on the internet? Is blocking Zoom making things more or less secure?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zoom got the attention because its user base and visibility increased massively during the pandemic. Admittedly it did have some low hanging fruit, but was it more or less of a threat to a business than your employees using something like &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Omegle">Omegle&lt;/a> for work?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we used the same metrics in which we judge Zoom and apply it to Windows or Linux those security teams would block almost all operating systems out there except maybe OpenBSD and BeOS.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="it-security-shouldnt-be-reactionary">IT security shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be reactionary&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>IT security needs to be evidence lead. Would you say now that Zoom, after 6 months of global usage it is not secure? Other than the occasional &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mvanhulten/status/1329885925862760450">person posting their Zoom codes&lt;/a>, which is the Video Conferencing equivalent of calling your S3 bucket &lt;code>big-bank-data&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So can how can we be less reactionary in future?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing is to &lt;a href="https://www.theregister.com/2020/04/03/zoom_security_improvements/">recognise that Zoom fixed a lot&lt;/a>, if not all, the issues that the security researchers were making a fuss over. Usually within days or weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where-as shouldn&amp;rsquo;t we &lt;a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/google-to-github-times-up-this-unfixed-high-severity-security-bug-affects-developers/">trust GitHub less&lt;/a> for having a long standing issue it&amp;rsquo;s been unable or unwilling to fix?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I&amp;rsquo;m proposing is instead of making decisions based upon what we read in the tech news this week, we measure good security practice from 3rd parties on how quickly and responsibly vulnerabilities in their products are announced and fixed, and be pragmatic about what your users need and expect from their IT.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://matt.copperwaite.net/about-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>matt@copperwaite.net (Matt Copperwaite)</author><guid>https://matt.copperwaite.net/about-me/</guid><description>&lt;!--alex ignore servant-->
&lt;p>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Matt Copperwaite. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for the United Kingdom Government for over 10 years both as a contractor and as a Civil Servant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started off as a Software Engineer, but got heavily involved in IT infrastructure projects and am now specialising in applying IT security to projects using Agile techniques.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>