<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Showcase on Matt Copperwaite</title><link>https://matt.copperwaite.net/showcase/</link><description>Recent content in Showcase on Matt Copperwaite</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>matt@copperwaite.net (Matt Copperwaite)</managingEditor><webMaster>matt@copperwaite.net (Matt Copperwaite)</webMaster><copyright>CC BY-SA 4.0</copyright><atom:link href="https://matt.copperwaite.net/showcase/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CharDiff</title><link>https://matt.copperwaite.net/showcase/chardiff/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 10:24:32 +0100</pubDate><author>matt@copperwaite.net (Matt Copperwaite)</author><guid>https://matt.copperwaite.net/showcase/chardiff/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/yamatt/python3-chardiff">CharDiff&lt;/a> is an easy-to-use tool to compare 2 strings and highlight the characters in them that are different.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This came about for a couple reasons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For one I had some very long strings I was working with at the time and I was having a lot of difficulty finding where they differed. I really struggled to find any tools that would allow me to find the difference between strings at a character level.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other reason was I was looking for a very quick project in Python3 that I could use to do things properly. By which I mean, have tested code, have it running in a CI/CD pipeline (I wanted to play with the GitHub Actions beta I&amp;rsquo;d got myself on to) and have it publish to PyPI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I even already have some &lt;a href="https://github.com/yamatt/python3-chardiff/issues/2">nice feedback from some users&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have seen subsequent posts around the web of tools like this, and there are &lt;a href="https://github.com/johannhof/difference.rs">definitely better ones out there&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t to be the best but to expand my knowledge. I now have a template for future projects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TV Show Chart</title><link>https://matt.copperwaite.net/showcase/tv-show-chart/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 17:14:32 +0100</pubDate><author>matt@copperwaite.net (Matt Copperwaite)</author><guid>https://matt.copperwaite.net/showcase/tv-show-chart/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://yamatt.github.io/tv-show-chart/">TV Show Chart&lt;/a> allows you to visualise the popularity of TV Show episodes across seasons using IMDb data and GitHub Actions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There used to be a website that did this for you. It seemed to go away. So I decided to write some quick hacks to make my own. It is really bare minimum to get it working.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It started off being nothing good or professional about the code behind the repo. I am not a front-end person at all, other than I like doing a bit of JavaScript from time to time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I personally prefer the IMDb popularity scores, but their API is functionally non-existent. So I wrote some Python to pull all the code together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Originally my plan was to store the episode data objects in maybe S3 or B2 and process the data in AWS Lambdas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However I could never get the Lambdas to complete in time and I was worried if the site became popular I would be paying for bandwidth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I then realised I might be able to store the data in GitHub, but the data as JSON was far too big. I seem to remember reading that there is a 2Gb limit on GitHub repo sizes. So I created my own proprietary format to store the data in a more succinct way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with static sites in GitHub and these work really well with GitHub Actions, commiting the code back to the repo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plus I read an article about grabbing &lt;a href="https://coviddata.github.io/coviddata/">Covid data using GitHub Actions on a schedule&lt;/a>. It really made me want to revisit this work since the data hadn&amp;rsquo;t been updated in months.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also found that GitHub Actions are way more powerful that Lambdas so I could run the scripts in a matter of minutes, which was nice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are definitely some UX improvements I would like to make so it&amp;rsquo;s possible to search for TV shows, but I need to do a bit of professionalisation first.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Filter Annoyances</title><link>https://matt.copperwaite.net/showcase/filter-annoyances/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 17:14:32 +0100</pubDate><author>matt@copperwaite.net (Matt Copperwaite)</author><guid>https://matt.copperwaite.net/showcase/filter-annoyances/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://yamatt.github.io/filter-annoyances/">Filter Annoyances&lt;/a> is some filters for uBlock Origin that I did not find in other filter lists.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is my first foray in to making uBlock Origin. I was at the time, and still do, wanted to remove the cookie and GDPR pop-ups but still use the site. These filters help facilitate that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a couple of built-in ones to uBlock such as &lt;a href="https://github.com/easylist/easylist">easylist cookie&lt;/a> and uBlock Annoyances, but these looked difficult to contribute to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did use &lt;a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/i-dont-care-about-cookies/">&lt;em>I don&amp;rsquo;t care about cookies&lt;/em>&lt;/a> for a little while, which worked fine, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find it&amp;rsquo;s source code anywhere, despite it saying it&amp;rsquo;s open source. So I thought to be safe I would stop using it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m kind of curious about ways you can test and validate uBlock Origin filters. It seems kind of difficult.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also found that the &lt;a href="https://github.com/gorhill/uBlock/wiki/Static-filter-syntax">filter syntax used in uBlock Origin comes from Adblock Plus&lt;/a>, and they can be very imprecise. But the uBlock Origin element picker tool is amazing. Some of the time I use it then copy the generated rule in to this repo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I chose (rather unusually for me) the CC0 license for these filters because I wanted to put them as much in to the public domain as possible, and because they are not really programmatic scripts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The distractions list is purely for things that take me away being productive on sites I use day-to-day. Kind of dark patterns really that keep you on their site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aggressive filter I&amp;rsquo;ve moved away from because it was too difficult to maintain and I kept having to switch off uBlock to see if the page worked, which then meant I saw ads.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>